Shreya Kanani

Manchester, United Kingdom

| shreyakanani27@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/shreya-kanani | +44 7776821872

GitHub - https://github.com/shreyakanani2

PROFILE

3+ years of experience in front-end development, very good experience in Angular and Typescript, Knowledge and experience in AG Grid Angular, strong knowledge and experience in HTML, CSS and Bootstrap, experience of Socket.io, Agora Web and NPM. Knowledge of Axure RP and User Experience Design. Looking for an opportunity in front end development, open to learn new technologies and tools.

IT SKILLS

- Angular
- Typescript
- JavaScript
- Nodejs
- ReactJs
- Openvidu
- CSS
- HTML
- BOOTSTRAP
- GIT

- ANGULAR MATERIAL
- AG GRID
- Kendo UI
- RXJS
- NPM
- Socket.io
- Agora web
- Unit testing Jasmine Karma
- Agile methodologies

WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer | DA Languages

Oct 2022 to Present

- **Build new features and components:** Involves developing new functionalities or enhancing existing ones. It typically includes writing code, creating user interfaces, implementing business logic, integrating with other systems, and ensuring proper documentation.
- Following Agile methodologies: Agile methodologies, such as Scrum, emphasize iterative and incremental development. They involve breaking down the work into smaller tasks or user stories, estimating effort, and organizing them into sprints or work cycles.
- **Sprint review and planning: -** Involved in sprint review and planning. Successfully completed task within sprint time.
- **Unit testing of components with Jasmine & Karma:** Developed testcases with jasmine and karma, maintained more than 80% code coverage.
- **Fixing bugs:** Involves debugging, identifying the cause of the bug, making necessary code changes, and testing the fix to ensure it resolves the issue without introducing new problems.

Frontend Engineer | Solution Analysts

May 2021 to Oct 2021

- Integrated Agora web with Angular for audio and video calls: Agora web, which is a real-time communication platform integrated it with angular project and developed audio and video call features.
- Used socket.io for chat, audio, and video calls: used socket events for sending message, joining users in the call.
- **Developed APIs with NodeJS and MySQL Workbench:** implemented admin panel API with Nodejs and integrated API it with angular.
- **Developed responsive web pages with bootstrap: -** designed pages using HTML, CSS and bootstrap.
- **Fixing bugs:** Involves debugging, identifying the cause of the bug, communicate with QA, making necessary code changes, and testing the fix to ensure it resolves the issue without introducing new problems.

• **Developed admin panel using Angular: -** Implemented add, edit and delete user feature, download reports, edit reports, show information on admin panel dashboard, draw chart and graph to show data.

Frontend Developer | I - Link Infosoft Consultants Private Limited

Jun 2019 to May 2021

- **Design and developed web pages:** Involves design and developing new functionalities. It typically includes writing code, creating user interfaces, implementing business logic, integrating with other systems.
- Solved issues and queries of customers: Involves debugging, identifying the cause of the bug, understanding of customers issue, making necessary code changes, and testing the fix to ensure it resolves the issue without introducing new problems.
- **Used of Angular Ag grid:** create, sort, and filter grid data, use of cell renderer, download pdf or csv, bind API data to Ag grid.
- Migrated web pages from Angular JS to Angular 9: convert same feature from Angular JS to Angular 9, maintain code quality, testing after converting web pages to ensure it is working as before.

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Coach | Coach Bright

April 2022 to July 2022

Coach Bright is a non-profit organization. It is a social mobility charity that exists to make education fairer.

- Did volunteering work as a coach in Coach Bright.
- managed and taught group of 5-6 students.

Professor | Mother Nature Science

September 2022 to October 2022

Mother Nature Science has offered the world's highest quality curriculum-linked science programs and activities for children aged 4-12.

taught science to children of age 4-6

EDUCATION & QUALIFICATIONS

University of Greenwich - Master's degree Computing & Information Systems 2021- 2022

Key Modules: Software Tools and Technique (80%), Project Management (70%),

System Modelling (75%), User Centered Web Engineering (70%)

Gujarat Technological University, Ahmedabad, India - B.E Information Technology 2015-2019

CGPA: 9.16

ACHIVEMENTS

- Secured Fifth rank in 3rd semester in GTU and second rank in 3rd semester in V.V.P. Engineering College.
- Secured second rank in programming skills during 6th semester of engineering from IT department.

STRENGTHS

- Hardworking, self-discipline, time-management
- Passionate to learn new technologies.
- Willing to take new opportunities and challenges.

· Leadership, dedication, and self-confidence

PERSONAL DETAILS

Gender: Female Nationality: Indian

Languages Known: English, Hindi, and Gujarati

Marital status: Married

INTERESTS

Reading, Travelling

DECLARATION

I am here by confirm that information given above is true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Your Sincerely,

Shreya Kanani

References available on request.